Hello English learners,
welcome back to another
sports lesson with
us here at English Pod,
my name is Marco and
I'm Erica and today we're
going to be talking
about a very interesting
and very difficult game
to play and it's golf.
So we've got some
golf vocabulary for you in
this lesson and I
think we better actually
look at a few vocabulary
words in vocabulary
preview before we
start with the dialogue.
Good vocabulary preview.
On vocabulary preview today we have three
words and the first one is aficionado.
aficionado.
And aficionado.
A golf aficionado.
Alright so this basically
is a very fancy word
of, it's a very fancy
way of saying a fan.
Yes someone who likes something a lot.
Ok so you are an aficionado, I like golf.
Yeah you can also be a wine aficionado.
Ok.
So it's kind of like a hobby.
Yeah you know a lot
about it and you like it.
And now our second word is
not anywhere in the dialogue.
No but we're going to use it when we explain
some of these words so you need to know
it.
Ok.
The word is club.
Club.
A golf club.
Ok so a golf club is the tool
you use to hit the golf ball.
Right so it's a long tube basically
that looks like a jay kind of.
Yeah so and you hit the ball with it.
So that's a golf club.
And now our third word is golf course.
Golf course.
A golf course.
A course.
So this is the area where you play golf.
Yeah it's like the golf field.
Exactly.
Yeah so it's a very big green
area where you play golf.
So those are the three words
we have for vocabulary preview.
So now we could listen to our dialogue for
the first time as we listen to our sports
announcers, Rick Fields and Bob Copeland
and see what happens on this occasion.
Good morning golf
aficionados my name is
Rick Fields and you guessed it I'm
here with my main man Bob Copeland.
Thank you Rick as
you can see ladies and
gentlemen we are here
in beautiful pebble beach
where the top golf is in the world
are vying to win the grand prize of one.
Million dollars.
Whoa that's a lot of cash.
Let's go to the course and
see how Tiger Woods is doing.
Alright we're here at
the eighth hole it's a
par fourth and has
some very difficult hazards
which many golfers
find difficult to avoid.
Although I did see Jack and Klaus hit
a hole in one on this very same hole.
Tiger Woods is about to tee off and
let's see if he has the same luck as Jack.
Tiger is asking his caddy for his
driver and he seems to be very nervous.
Oh no not a good swing at all
it's definitely not his day today.
On the seventh hole he
got a bogey and before
that he barely made par he will
definitely not get a birdie on this shot.
It seems that his ball has flown
somewhere deep into the trees.
He's having a hard
time finding it and even
his caddy has climbed
a tree to try and spot
it.
So we're pretty exciting ending to that
dialogue there a bear on the golf course.
Yeah I wonder if Tiger's okay.
I sure hope so because it would
be a huge loss to the world of golf.
Right so we did learn
a lot about golf because
they used some very
specific and technical
words for golf so let's look at
these now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right so the
announcers were talking
about the game and
they're talking about the
course and they're here on the eighth hole
and they said that last time Jack Nicholas
hit a hole in one hole in one hole
in one hole in one okay a hole in one.
So this is when you
hit the ball once and the
ball goes in the hole
exactly so it's something
very difficult to do
right a hole in one I've
certainly never made
one okay so sometimes
it's also called an ace so it can be a hole
in one or called an ace okay now for our
second word now once we get to the hole
to the ninth hole or the tenth hole we have
to tee off to tee off tee off so when you
tee off you begin playing right so it's the
very first instance
where you put the little
ball on the tee and
you hit the ball for
the first time exactly so to tee off now
another golf vocabulary they were they were
talking about a caddy right a caddy a caddy
now a caddy is a person yes it's the person
who carries your golf
clubs exactly so he
carries your bag your
golf clubs and basically
helps you while you're playing golf yeah he
tells you which way you should hit the ball
and maybe you know
gives you a nice cold drink
and he looks after
you very good so that's
a caddy and now the caddy since he has to
carry all the golf clubs Tiger Woods asked
him for his driver a driver driver a driver
now a driver is a type of golf club right
it's not a person no no it's a type of golf
club and it's a very big and heavy golf
club that is used to tee off so it's used
to hit the ball a very long way yes that is
called the driver okay so in the next thing
they were talking about were some different
types of scores that
you could get on a hole
and the first one they
mentioned was par
okay so you can make par okay or the par
of the course can be four okay very good so
basically the par is the
maximum number of
swings or strokes you
can make before putting
the ball into the
hole right so it's like
it's like the right so
when the when the when
a hole is par for you
should only hit the
ball four times four
times or less yeah very
good now if you don't make par there are
some options you can make a bogey alright
a bogey a bogey now
sometimes the golf course
is very difficult yeah
so instead of putting
the ball in the hole let's say in four turns
yeah you do it in five okay so it's one
over par one over par
that's bad yeah that's
bad because you get a point so it's kind
of strange because in golf the more points
you have the worst you
are so that is a bogey
now they also talked about a birdie birdie
is the opposite if you hit one under par
so that's good yeah that's good because you
have minus one one less than par alright
so this is actually
a lot of weird crazy
strange language birdie
bogey catty driver why
don't we listen to
the dialogue one more
time to help us understand
good morning golf
aficionados my name
is Rick Fields and you
guessed it I'm here with
my main man Bob Copeland
thank you Rick as
you can see ladies and
gentlemen we are here
in beautiful pebble beach
where the top golfers
in the world are vying
to win the grand prize
of one million dollars
whoa that's a lot of
cash let's go to the
course and see how tiger
woods is doing alright
we're here at the
eighth hole it's a par four
and has some very
difficult hazards which
many golfers find difficult to avoid although
I did see Jack Nicklaus hit a hole in
one of this very same
hole tiger woods is
about to tee off and
let's see if he has the
same luck as Jack
tiger is asking his catty
for his driver and he
seems to be very nervous
oh no not a good
swing at all it is definitely
not his day today on the seventh hole he
got a bogey and before that he barely made
par he'll definitely
not get a birdie on this
shot it seems that his
ball is flown somewhere
deep in the trees he
is having a hard time
finding it and even his catty has climbed
a tree to try and spot it oh no a bear run
tiger run somebody
call animal control all
right great so I think
it's clear now what type
of rules they have in golf and how it works
so why don't we take a look now at some of
the phrases that we heard in the dialogue
and fluency builder fluency builder okay
well one of the phrases
I want to talk about
is something that Bob
Copeland said he said
as you can see ladies
and gentlemen we're here
at beautiful pebble
beach okay as you can see
as you can see so this
usually goes in the beginning
of a sentence yeah
it's a way to say I know
you can see this I'm
telling you something you
know okay so maybe
I'm showing you my house
and I can say as you
can see our living room is
very spacious yes so
this is actually a really
helpful phrase it can help
you sound really native
like so why not we hear
some examples of how it's
used example one as
you can see we recently
remodeled our entire kitchen
example two as you can
see here the damage to
the building is very serious
example three as you
can see the hairstylist
made a mistake when
cutting my hair all right
great so as you can see
now for our second phrase
well tiger woods wasn't
doing very well and the
announcer said it's not
his day it's not his day
it's not his day today
all right so when it's
not your day um you're
having a bad time or a
bad day right maybe
you're having difficulties or
you're having bad luck
that day yeah so for example
today um I had a headache
and I ripped my pants
and I spilled coffee
on myself so it really
wasn't my day okay it's
not your day today no
great phrase and also very
common and makes you
sound very native that's
right now the last phrase
um similar to it's not
your day we also heard
that tiger was having a
hard time okay to have a
hard time to have a hard
time now if you have a
hard time with something
you have difficulty with
it okay now it's not
only related to golf right
of course you can talk
about anything like this
so I'm having a hard
time understanding what
this word means okay
or when I was in school
I had a hard time with
math all right me too
so to have a hard time
means that you have
difficulties with something
so great phrases great
words and let's listen
to this dialogue for the
last time and then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more about golf
Good morning golf
aficionados my name is Rick
Fields and you guessed it
I'm here with my main man
Bob Copeland thank you
Rick as you can see ladies
and gentlemen we are
here in beautiful pebble
beach where the top golf
is in the world are vying
to win the grand prize
of one million dollars
whoa that's a lot of cash let's go to the
course and see how tiger woods is doing
all right we're here
at the eight hole it's uh
par four and has some
very difficult hazards which
many golfers find
difficult to avoid although I
did see Jack in class hit
a hole a one on this very
same hole tiger woods
is about to see off and
let's see if he has the
same luck as Jack tiger
is asking his caddy for
his driver and he seems
to be very nervous oh
no not a good swing at all
it's definitely not
his day-to-day on the
seventh hole he got a
bogey and before that he
barely made par he will
definitely not get a birdie
on this shot it seems
that his ball has flown
somewhere deep into the trees he's having
a hard time finding it and even as caddy is
cloned a tree to try and
spot it oh no up there
we're talking run
somebody call out of control
all right so Marco I know
that in um the western
business world golf is
actually super important
for your career isn't it
well many times you know
when you see in movies
or the stereotype is that
business is done on a
golf course yeah and yeah
it is true many times you
know people will invite
you out to a golf course
and you'll be playing a
game and you know
talking business and relaxing
at the same time so
maybe you you negotiate a
deal out on the golf
course exactly and of course
if you lose it's a good
thing because then the deal
will pull through uh-huh
okay well actually I know
that is so important
for people um who are
wanting to do well in
business and many people who
don't speak English
as their first language
take golf English lessons
right so not only golf
lessons like how to play
golf but also in English
like how to talk about
golf how to um you know
talk to other people and
make deals while you're
on the golf course yeah
because like in many
other sports golf has
also it's slaying and it's
terms and stuff so yeah
it's very interesting and
it's one of those cultural
things that's right so
if you have any questions
or comments about today's
lesson why don't you visit
our website at englishpod.
com right we're always
there to answer any questions
or doubts you might have and until
next time we'll see you there goodbye